♪♪
♪ ♪
ウィル：こんにちは、「アプリの予約注文の新機能は何ですか？」へようこそ。私の名前はLOであり、私はApp Store Connectチームのソフトウェアエンジニアです。
Will: Hi, welcome to "What's New in App Pre-orders?" My name's Will Lo, and I'm a software engineer on the App Store Connect team.
予約注文用のアプリを提供することは、今後のアプリリリースの興奮を生み出す強力な方法です。
Offering your app for pre-order can be a powerful way to generate excitement for your upcoming app release.
アプリを予約注文できるようにすると、その製品ページはApp Storeで公開されます。アプリは、ダウンロードのためにリリースされる前にアプリを購入できます。
When you make your app available for pre-order, its product page becomes published on the App Store, where your app can be purchased before it's released for download.
リリース日には、顧客に通知され、アプリはデバイスで自動的にダウンロードされます。
On release day, your customers will be notified and your app will be automatically downloaded on their devices.
このセッションでは、App Store Connectで行っているエキサイティングな更新についてお話したいと思います。
In this session, I want to talk about some exciting updates that we're making in App Store Connect.
今年は、地域ベースで予約注文のためにアプリを提供する機能を提供しています。
This year, we're giving you the ability to offer your app for pre-order on a regional basis.
これらの更新により、予約注文のためにアプリをどこでどのように公開するかを選択する柔軟性が高まります。
These updates will give you more flexibility to choosing where and how you publish your apps for pre-order.
そのため、未発表のアプリの場合、可能な限り、予約注文用に公開する特定の領域を選択できます。
So for an unreleased app, you'll be able to choose specific regions to publish for pre-order, just as you can today.
ただし、この新しい柔軟性を使用すると、ソフトローンチまたは限定リリースとして、最初にアプリをいくつかの地域にリリースし、選択した他の地域でアプリを予約注文することもできます。
But with this new flexibility, you'll also be able to first release your app to a few regions, as a soft launch or limited release, and then offer your app for pre-order in any other region you choose.
また、アプリの範囲を拡大し続けると、予約注文を使用して、各追加地域で興奮をさらに構築できます。
And as you continue expanding the reach of your app, you can use pre-order to further build excitement in each additional region.
それでは、App Store Connectを使用していくつかの例を進めて、これらの予約注文を設定しましょう。
So let's walk through a few examples using App Store Connect to set up these pre-orders.
この最初の例では、Backyard Birdsは、リリースに関する興奮を生み出すために予約注文として公開したい真新しい未発表のアプリです。
In this first example, Backyard Birds is a brand new, unreleased app that you want to publish as a pre-order to generate some excitement around its release.
9月1日に裏庭の鳥をリリースしたいとし、製品ページの詳細がすべてApp Store Connectに設定されているとしましょう。
Let's say that you want to release Backyard Birds on September 1, and that you've got your product page details all set up on App Store Connect.
最初の予約注文を設定するには、価格設定と可用性ページにアクセスして、[設定]設定をクリックできます。
To set up your first pre-order, you can head to the Pricing and Availability page and click Set Up Availability.
次に、このダイアログ内で、特定の国または地域で 予約注文を選択します。
Then, within this dialog, select Pre-Order in Specific Countries or Regions.
これが、9月1日に予想されるリリース日を入力する場所です。
Here's where you would enter your expected release date, September 1.
予想されるリリース日は、将来最大180日間になる可能性があります。
The expected release date can be up to 180 days in the future.
次に、アプリが予約注文できる米国を選択します。
Next, you would select the United States, where your app will be made available for pre-order.
最後に、この確認画面が表示され、予想されるリリース日とアプリが事前注文できる場所を表示します。
And finally, you'll see this confirmation screen, showing you the expected release date and where the app will be available for pre-order.
そして、それに伴い、このアプリは、9月1日の予想されるリリース日で、米国で予約注文のために適切に設定されました。
And with that, the app is now properly set up for pre-order in the United States with an expected release date of September 1.
そのとき、顧客に通知され、アプリが自動的にデバイスにダウンロードされます。
That's when your customers will be notified, and your app will be automatically downloaded to their devices.
それでは、少し下にスクロールして、可用性セクションを見てみましょう。これにより、各国または地域でのアプリのリリースステータスの完全な詳細なビューが表示されます。
Now, let's scroll down a bit and take a look at the Availability section, which now gives you a complete detailed view of the app's release status in each country or region.
したがって、アプリが販売の準備ができているか、予約注文のために公開されているか、または利用できないかにかかわらず、このページはそれを理解するのに役立ちます。
So whether the app is ready for sale, published for pre-order, or otherwise unavailable, this page will help you understand that.
この例では、このアプリは複数の地域で利用できます。
In this example, this app is available in multiple regions.
ただし、アプリが何らかの形で利用できない場合は、各地域で何が起こっているかを正確に伝えるこのようなステータスラベルが表示されます。
But if your app is somehow unavailable, you'll see a status label like this one that tells you exactly what's happening in each region.
そのため、先行予約用の新しいアプリの公開をセットアップする方法です。
So that's how you would set up publishing a brand new app for pre-order.
次に、サンプルアプリのシナリオを再考しましょう。
Now, let's re-imagine the scenario for our example app.
ジャストカナダで公開された裏庭の鳥が限定リリースであったとしましょう。
Let's say that Backyard Birds was a limited release, published in just Canada.
最初の反応は非常に素晴らしいものであり、来年3月1日のリリース日が予定されているリリース日で、その可用性を米国に拡大したいと思います。
The initial reaction has been really great, and you would like to expand its availability to the United States, with a scheduled release date of March 1 of next year.
それを予約注文として設定する方法を歩きましょう。
Let's walk through how we can set that up as a pre-order.
まず、価格設定と可用性ページ内から、アプリの可用性セクションで 管理を押すことができます。
First, from within the Pricing and Availability page, you can hit Manage under the App Availability section.
ここでは、現在カナダで入手可能であることがわかります。
Here, we can see that it's currently available in Canada.
したがって、米国で予約注文を公開するには、最初にセットアップを予約注文することができます。
So to publish your pre-order in the United States, you can first hit Set Up Pre-order.
次に、2024年3月1日に予想されるリリース日を入力します。
Then, you'll enter your expected release date, March 1st, 2024.
App Storeですでに公開されているアプリの場合、予想されるリリース日は将来365日までになります。
For an app that's already published on the App Store, the expected release date can be up to 365 days in the future.
次に、米国を選択して、予約注文を公開します。
Next, select the United States to publish your pre-order in.
最後に、この確認画面が表示され、変更の要約が表示されます。
Finally, you'll see this confirmation screen, showing you a summary of your changes.
これらの変更は、24時間以内にApp Storeに表示されます。
These changes will appear on the App Store within 24 hours.
ここでは、アプリの更新された予約注文の可用性を確認できます。
Here, you can see your app's updated pre-order availability.
公開された列は、予約注文が本日米国で公開されていることを示していますが、スケジュールされたリリース日列は、アプリが現在3月1日にリリースされる予定であることを示しています。
The Published column shows you that your pre-order has been published in the United States today, while the Scheduled Release Date column shows you that the app is currently scheduled to be released on March 1.
これで、アプリの可用性ページ内から、すでに設定している予約注文も更新できます。
Now, from within the App Availability page, you can update the pre-orders that you've already set up as well.
最後の例を進めて、公開された予約注文を更新します。
We'll walk through a final example and update the pre-order that was published.
編集を押すと、最初に3つの異なる設定を更新できるダイアログが表示されます。
If you hit Edit, you'll first be presented with a dialog that lets you update three different settings.
まず、アプリのリリース日を更新できます。
First, you can update your app's release date.
この例アプリはすでにカナダでリリースされているため、米国の予約注文が最初に公開された365日から最大365日まで、将来の日付を選択できます。
Since this example app was already released in Canada, you can choose any date in the future, up to 365 days from when your US pre-order was originally published.
次に、すぐに予約注文をリリースすることもできます。
Next, you can also release your pre-order immediately.
顧客に通知され、アプリはデバイスにダウンロードされます。
Your customers will be notified and your app will be downloaded to their devices.
アプリをリリースしたら、公開した地域で再度予約注文できるようにすることはできません。
Remember, once you release your app, it can't be made available for pre-order again in the regions that you've published in.
最後に、その地域のApp Storeから予約注文を削除することを選択できます。
Finally, you can choose to remove your pre-order from the App Store in that region.
App Storeで予約注文用のアプリを公開した後、予約注文アプリのマーケティングや、事前オーダーのパフォーマンスの追跡に興味がある場合があります。
After publishing your app for pre-order on the App Store, you may be interested in marketing your pre-order app or in tracking the performance of your pre-orders.
予約注文アプリを販売するには、これらのローカライズされたバッジをWebサイトまたはマーケティング資料で使用して、人々を製品ページに直接リンクできます。
To market your pre-order app, you can use these localized badges on your website or in your marketing materials to directly link people to your product page.
予約注文アプリも検索を通じて発見でき、App Storeの今日、ゲーム、またはアプリタブで紹介できます。
Pre-order apps are discoverable through search as well, and may be featured on the Today, Games, or Apps tabs on the App Store.
予約注文のパフォーマンスは、アプリ分析内から追跡できます。この分析では、日付ごとに購入した予約注文の数を見ることができます。
The performance of your pre-orders can be tracked from within App Analytics, where you can find the number of purchased pre-orders by date and by region.
また、これらの新しい更新により、予約注文アプリのカスタム製品ページと製品ページ最適化テストを実行できます。
And, with these new updates, you'll be able to run custom product pages and product page optimization tests for any pre-order app.
カスタム製品ページのパフォーマンスと最適化テストは、アプリ分析内から追跡することもできます。
The performance of your custom product pages and optimization tests can also be tracked from within App Analytics.
したがって、これらの更新は、予約注文のためにアプリをどこでどのように公開するかを選択する際に、全体的な柔軟性を高めることができます。
So to wrap up, these updates will give you more flexibility overall in choosing where and how you publish your apps for pre-order.
App Store Connectを使用して、これらの事前注文を設定および管理できます。
You can use App Store Connect to set up and manage these pre-orders.
そして最後に、私がカバーした機能は、App Store Connect APIによってもサポートされます。
And finally, the functionality that I covered will be supported by the App Store Connect API as well.
もっと学ぶことに興味がある場合は、wwdc23の「App Store Connectの新機能」、またはThe Tech Talk「Appの発見とマーケティングの始まり」を必ずチェックしてください。
If you're interested in learning more, please be sure to check out "What's new in App Store Connect", from WWDC23, or the tech talk "Get started with app discovery and marketing".
そして、いつものように、フィードバックアシスタントに提供できるフィードバックを歓迎します。
And as always, we welcome any feedback that you may provide on Feedback Assistant.
見てくれてありがとう、そして残りのWWDCをお楽しみください！
Thanks for watching, and enjoy the rest of WWDC!
♪♪
♪ ♪